<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>gerbyzation</title>
    <description>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</description>
    <link>http://gerbyzation.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://gerbyzation.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2014 13:49:28 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2014 13:49:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>GPS drawing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This week we talked about GPS drawings. This is the practise of walking a figure and keeping a record of your GPS locations so these can be digitally visualised into your ‘drawing’. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the characteristics of a GPS drawing is the influence the geoography has on your drawing. Because of (articifial or natural) obstacles forces you to &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GPS drawings are always influenced by the geography of the location where it’s drawn. Natural or artificial obstacles make it impossible to draw perfect figures which gives that every drawing has a ‘signature’ of the location where it was drawn. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me the appleal of GPS drawing seems to be in the fact that you can see it as a struggle between you and the location. Humans have always had a tendency to leave a trail and shape their environment to their benefits, but &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After looking at the map Robert and I decided to walk around the shopping area and draw a shopping bag around it. We drew a quick sketch on the map in photoshop:
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/DAT203_gps_plan.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;The planned route&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little while later we walked the route and you can see the result on the picture below. Because our drawing is on a relative low scale the line is quite wobbly and sometimes we had to divert a bit from our planned route. Also we had a little glitch at the end which added some random lines through the crossing. 
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/DAT203_gps_walk.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The map which shows our GPS drawing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested (and as proof that we did do the walk :) ), you can find the original GPS data here: &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/other/shoppingbag.xml&quot;&gt;GPS data (XML)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2014 22:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://gerbyzation.github.io/dat203/2014/10/27/GPS-drawing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gerbyzation.github.io/dat203/2014/10/27/GPS-drawing.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>dat203</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The music surrounding us</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday Mike gave a presentation for the module DAT201 (Strageties for Art &amp;amp; Technology) about Sound Art, covering several topics and talked about some of the questions. One of the questions was about noise: ‘Is noise music?’. That question goes back to the question ‘What is noise?’. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today’s session was a perfect continuation of this topic. We talked about environmental sound with the goal to be more aware of the sounds surrounding you and appriciative of its characteristics. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Let’s walk together through a great modern capital, with the ear more attentive than the eye, and we will vary the pleasures of our sensibilities by distinguishing among the gurglings of water, air and gas inside metallic pipes, the rumblings and rattlings of engines breathing with obvious animal spirits, the rising and falling of pistons, the stridency of mechanical saws, the loud jumping of trolleys on their rails, the snapping of whips, the whipping of flags. We will have fun imagining our orchestration of department stores’ sliding doors, the hubbub of the crowds, the different roars of railroad stations, iron foundries, textile mills, printing houses, power plants and subways.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Luigi Russolo, &lt;em&gt;The Art of Noise&lt;/em&gt;, 1913&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a lot of stuff happening around you, but brains are really good at filtering away the ‘backgroundnoise’ to help you focus. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went out and walked around campus with an audiorecorder listening to the sound around us and trying to capture some of those sounds. Quite a lot of sound is too soft or far away to clearly make a record of. But we were able to record some interesting sounds in the workshop, UPSU, outside buildings and from a watertap. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we imported the sounds into Audacity and played around with them. I played around with several effects, among which the ‘Paulstretch’. By stretching the audio out, you can get some really nice ambient sounds. I’ve also done some other things and created a small composition with the different sounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p /&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
&lt;audio src=&quot;/assets/audio/fieldrecording_LQ.mp3&quot; preload=&quot;none&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2014 23:43:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://gerbyzation.github.io/dat203/2014/10/09/fieldrecording.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gerbyzation.github.io/dat203/2014/10/09/fieldrecording.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>dat203</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Psychogeography - &#39;Falling in love with places&#39;</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the first practical session of Reflexive Design Mike talked about ‘Psychogeography’, which is defined as ‘the study of the precise laws and specific effects of the geographical environment, consciously organized or not, on the emotions and the behavior of individuals’. Practically that means making geographical distinction between areas based on emotions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The emotional judgement of locations is something I recognise doing. Two weeks ago I moved from the Netherlands to Plymouth, so I have loads of stuff to discover here. In the first week you get a lot of impressions and feelings when walking through Plymouth. But in a short period as a week or two things start to feel normal and you pay less attention to your surroundings and how it makes you feel. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As noted by the worksheet the main practise to do psychogeography is &lt;em&gt;‘derive’&lt;/em&gt;: ‘an aimless wandering with senses open to how certain areas make you feel’. We will be using a slightly different approach, We’ll draw a circle on the map and plan a route that follows the circle as close as possible. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/DAT203_psychogeo_map.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;The route drawn on the map&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I just moved to Plymouth it was a bit difficult to follow the assignment strictly and do an imaginary walk and divede the map up in area’s that have different feelings. So we skipped that one and went straight to the real walk!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marcin and I did the walk according to the route we drew on the map, here you can find some pictures and our findings noted in keypoints:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Crossing Royal parade &amp;amp; Armada way / House of Fraser
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Open space gives a sense of freedom&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;People are busy with their own things (i.e. buying and selling goods)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;gives a sense of capitalism&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;building made of massive concrete blocks make you feel small and unwelcome&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;feels hurried and bussy
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/DAT203_psychogeo_01.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Photo 01&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/DAT203_psychogeo_02.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Photo 02&quot; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Crossing Armada way &amp;amp; Cornwall Str.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Trees and greenery gives more social area feeling&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;even in the middle of the shopping district with loads of people, feels like a different place&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;gives rest and more pieace, friendly&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;escape from the hurry (rush)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;feels like an oasis&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Motorway
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;in between places&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;people don’t pay attention, just want to go somewhere&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;place of transition (transition of spaces)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;don’t want to stay there&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;people are not really ‘in a place’
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/DAT203_psychogeo_03.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Photo 03&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/DAT203_psychogeo_04.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Photo 04&quot; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Oxford place
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;residential are under construction, makes you feel unsafe (something may fall on you off the building)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;cautions&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;people come here to get rest after day of work&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;not much decoration, greenery is rare&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;boring fronts&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;poles with phonelines, association with slumms
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/DAT203_psychogeo_05.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Photo 05&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/DAT203_psychogeo_06.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Photo 06&quot; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Victoria park
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;welcoming place&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;sense of freedom&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;quietness, escape from the city&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;place for leisure&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;place where you can relax, do nothing, think
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/DAT203_psychogeo_07.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Photo 07&quot; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Clarence court/Abbey thingy
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;functional but boring buildings&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;inconsistent with different styles of buildings&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;untidy
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/DAT203_psychogeo_08.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Photo 08&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/DAT203_psychogeo_09.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Photo 09&quot; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adelaide str.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;looks like it used to be centre of a small town&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;quiet and peacefull with wide open alleyways&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;unique
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/DAT203_psychogeo_10.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Photo 10&quot; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Union str.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;more industrial&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;bussy, occupied by people and cars&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;feels like we’re back in the city&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;glory days are gon for part in direction of city centre&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;contrast between investment area and poverty/abandoned
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/DAT203_psychogeo_11.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Photo 11&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/DAT203_psychogeo_12.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Photo 12&quot; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Citroen dealer
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;much more cozy, more trees and greenery&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;varying buildings&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;looked after, clean
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/DAT203_psychogeo_13.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Photo 13&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/DAT203_psychogeo_14.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Photo 14&quot; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;End of Hillbay Rd / roundabout
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;open spaces&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;commercial&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;neutral feeling
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/DAT203_psychogeo_15.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Photo 15&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/DAT203_psychogeo_16.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Photo 16&quot; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Millbay / West Hoe str.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;peacefull&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;mixture of pretty/ugly, history and new (see photo)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;cool trees
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/DAT203_psychogeo_17.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Photo 17&quot; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The cressent / Notte str.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;We are back in bussy city centre&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;don’t feel like you want to spend much time in here as it makes you tired
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/DAT203_psychogeo_18.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Photo 18&quot; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2014 16:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://gerbyzation.github.io/dat203/2014/10/06/psychogeography.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gerbyzation.github.io/dat203/2014/10/06/psychogeography.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>dat203</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New site, new uni, new exciting stuff!</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;hi&quot;&gt;Hi!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;THis is a new version of my personal site, a work in progress!
For now I’ll be mainly posting for the DAT203 Reflexive Design module from Digital Art &amp;amp; Technology. Later I’ll improve the site and expand it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year I did the course Communcation &amp;amp; Multimedia Design at Avans in Breda, I finished my first year and received my propaedeutics. But I’ve quit CMD and joined the second year of &lt;a href=&quot;http://digitalartandtechnology.co.uk/&quot; title=&quot;Digital Art &amp;amp; Technology&quot;&gt;Digital Art &amp;amp; Technology&lt;/a&gt; at Plymouth University, which I’m really excited about! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve started for a few weeks now and I really enjoy it. We’re already doing some interesting stuff and there is much more exciting stuff coming :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 23:21:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://gerbyzation.github.io/2014/10/05/work-in-progress.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gerbyzation.github.io/2014/10/05/work-in-progress.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
